Tanish Sharma

Data Scientist

Experienced Analytics Professional with an enthusiasm for solving challenging business problems with the help of data-driven insights. With experience in NLP text classification, sentiment analysis, and computer vision projects. Successfully delivered a project for client Clarins involving text classification and sentiment analysis of customer reviews, resulting in improved product insights and customer satisfaction. Additionally, a fashion recommendation system was built using ResNet-50 (CNN) and KNN for personalized outfit recommendations.



sharma.tanish096@gmail.com



+91-89686-32732



www.linkedin.com/tanish-sharma-367102144/

SKILLS

Business Strategy

Decision Making

Conflict Resolver

Team Player

Adaptability

TECHNICALSKILLS

Python (NumPy, pandas, sklearn)





















NLP (Deep Learning, tensorflow, keras)













WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist – Analytics Insights

The Math Company

03/2022 - Present Achievements/Task

- Successfully delivered a project for client Clarins involving text classification and sentiment analysis of customer reviews, resulting in improved product insights and customer satisfaction.
- Built a fashion recommendation system using ResNet-50 (CNN) and KNN for personalized outfit recommendations. Deployed on Stream lit webpage.
- Build a web app for client Takeda (health pharma ind.) using codx owned by Mathco's.
- Build a propensity model to gain deep insights into customer behavior across various segments.

Exec. Data Scientist- Analytics Insights

Nielsen

05/2021-02/2022 Achievements/Task

- Data Scientist role: Involves fusing two datasets and generating a linkage file for further analysis. Python-based: The fusion process is executed using Python, employing multiple distance metrics.
- Scripting and version control: All scripting is performed in VScode, with source control managed through GitLab.

Data Analyst

Infosys

08/2018-05/2021 Achievements/Task

Worked as a Data Analyst in Infosys' Research and Development team, focusing on the healthcare platform. Tasks included data cleansing, data mining, data profiling, data exploratory analysis, data standardization, and data normalization.

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Electronics

Guru Nanak Dev University, Amritsar

07/2014 - 06/2018

CERTIFICATES

- Completed Computer Vision Fundamentals with Google Cloud.
- Certificated in Problem-Solving (Basic) by Hackerrank.
- 6 Weeks of training in SQL with DATA Science by UC DAVIS.
- 6 weeks training of in Data Analysis with Python by IBM.
- 6 Weeks of training in SQL with DATA Science by UC DAVIS.